

+91-9836641229



jayantaduttajisce@gmail.com



Banipur, Rabindra Sarani, PS-Habra, North 24 Parganas, PIN-743233, West Bengal.

# Jayanta Dutta

Senior Software Automation QA Analyst

### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

7 years and 8 months of experience working in Automation Framework Development, Scripting and Script Maintenance. Proficient in development and maintenance of automation scripts of Web, Desktop, Client-server applications, and Web Services using Selenium WebDriver, Ranorex Studio, SOAP UI, Rest Assured, Postman and ReadyApi. Possesses B.Tech degree in Information Technology .Impeccable written, verbal, communication skills, and excellent interpersonal skills.



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Willis Towers Watson

Duration: Jan 2023- Present Current Designation: Senior Analyst Current Location: Kolkata

# Previous Organizations PricewaterhouseCoopers Pvt Ltd (IN)

Duration: Aug 2021- Dec 2022 (1 year 4 months)

## Cognizant Technology Solutions India Pvt. Ltd

Duration: May 2016- Aug 2021 (5 years & 3



# **TECHNICAL SKILLSET**

#### **Testing Tools**

Selenium, Ranorex, SOAP UI, Ready API, Postman, Rest Assured, Rest#, BDD-Specflow, Cucumber Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio

### Languages

Java, Groovy,C#, jQuery & JS

### IDE

Eclipse, Ranorex Studio, Visual Studio.

### **Test Framework**

BDD, KDD, Hybrid UI & API Automation Framework, TestNG, Rest-Assured, Ranorex.

### Methodology

Agile, Waterfall

### **Test Management & Defect Tracking**

JIRA, Microsoft TFS, Microsoft Azure

### **Version Control**

Git,,BitBucket

# Data Base

 $\mathsf{MSSQL}\,\mathsf{,}\mathsf{MySql}$ 



# **PERSONAL DOSSEIR**

Gender: Male.

Date of Birth: 23<sup>rd</sup> June 1992.

### Languages:

English: Read, Write, Speak Bengali: Read, Write, Speak Hindi: Read, Write, Speak

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



- 7 years and 7 months of Automation Testing (Web UI) Experience using Selenium in Java for Different BDD, KDD, TDD & Hybrid Frameworks.
- 6+ years of experience in Rest API functional and automation testing using API testing tool (Soap UI, Ready API, POSTMAN)
- 5 years of experience in Automation Framework development, Assessment, and setup roadmap for improving the maturity.
- 9 months of experience in Mobile Automation using Appium & Android studio
- 1 year of experience in leading a 5-member automation team.
- 5 years of experience in JIRA and Microsoft Azure DevOps (TFS)
- 1.5 years of experience in SAP Automation (SD and CRM) using Ranorex Studio
- 1 year of experience in SAP S/4 Hana Business suite automation (EM, Replicon & Concur)
- 1 year of experience in Guidewire Policy Centre Automation in Ranorex Studio.
- Extensive experience in developing Test Plans, Test Strategy, Test Cases, Test Matrices, Requirements Traceability, Test Reports and documentation of Manual and Automated Tests.
- Good exposure in SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle) and STLC (Software Test Life Cycle) –Agile and Waterfall.
- Experienced in using Version Control systems -Tortoise SVN and GIT.
- 4 Years of Experience in using SAP ERP Based business Modules

### **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**



### B. Tech in Information Technology

JIS College of Engineering (University-WBUT). DGPA 8.59, Year-2011-2015

# 12<sup>th</sup> (Higher Secondary)

West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education, Year -2010 –70.43%.

# 10<sup>th</sup> (Secondary)

West Bengal Board of Secondary Education, Year -2008 –78.22%.

## PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS



# Spot Award – Thank You/ Good Job Individual

PricewaterhouseCoopers Pvt Ltd (IN)

Year- 2022

### **QE&A Delivery Excellence Award**

Cognizant Technology Solutions and Canadian Automobile Association.

Year- 2017

### **Automation Champ Award**

Cognizant Technology Solutions and Canadian Automobile Association.

Year-2020.



# SAP S4/HANA EM, REPLICON, CONCUR UI & REST API AUTOMATION

**Role**: QA Automation Script Developer, **Client** – Major German based Audit organization. Methodology – Agile **Description**: SAP S/4 Hana Business suite combines Engagement Management, Replicon & Concur and as an automation engineer, I have created the API & Web UI (Selenium - Java) based test library to test the integration between the applications.

- Designing the Web Automation Framework in Selenium-Java using TestNG-Selenium based Test Suite for the S/4 Hana EM and FICO modules
- Preparing Web Service Automation Scripts using Rest Assured and generating html reports using jQuery.
- Designing Test scripts for both UI and web services.
- Deeply monitoring script quality and reporting defects as when required.
- Using version control tool GIT to coordinate team-development.
- Attended weekly Scrum calls with client and keep them updated adhering the organization policies and standards

**Tools:** Selenium – JAVA, Postman (Functional) ,Rest Assured- (Automation)

### SAP IN-SPRINT & REGRESSION UI & API AUTOMATION

Role: QA Automation Script Developer, Client – Major Canada based P&C insurance client, Methodology – Waterfall. Description: SAP Sales and Distribution (SAP SD) is a core functional module in SAP ERP Central Component (ECC) that allows organizations to store and manage customer- and product-related data. Working in conjunction with the other modules, SAP SD enables an order-to-cash cycle business process. This automation project involves all the sales processes and Transactions in SAP SD & SAP CRM.

- Preparing Test Automaton Framework in Ranorex Studio 8.1
- Assessment and setup roadmap for improving the maturity.
- Preparing API Process Automation Scripts using SoapUi & ReadyAPI and generating html reports using Groovy Script to Test the entire API Process integration is working as expected.
- Designing Test scripts for both Test case and process automation.
- Leading a team of 5 member
- Preparing BDD framework and scripts for In-sprint Automation.
- Deeply monitoring script quality and reporting defects as when required

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY: SAP CRM and SD, Ranorex Studio, MSSQL Server, Spec flow, SoapUi, ReadyApi

### **GUIDEWIRE POLICY CENTER AUTOMATION**

**Role**: QA Automation Script Developer, **Client** – CAA (Canada), **Duration** – June 2017 – June-2018, **Methodology** – Agile.

**Description:** Guidewire PolicyCenter is a flexible underwriting and policy management system that enables property/casualty insurers to grow business profitably by improving efficiency, while responding with agility to market opportunities and enhancing relationships with agents and customers. This automation project involves all the policy lifecycle processes and transactions in guidewire 7 policy center.

- Preparing Test Automaton Framework in Ranorex Studio 8.1
- Assessment and setup roadmap for improving the maturity.
- Designing Test scripts for both Test case and process automation.
- Deeply monitoring script quality and reporting defects as when required.

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY: GUIDEWIRE 7, Ranorex Studio.